Now let's talk about the syntax of first order logic.
现在我们来讨论一阶逻辑的语法
And like in propositional logic, we have sentences,
与命题逻辑一样 我们有语句
which describe facts that are true or false.
描述真或假的事实
But unlike propositional logic, we also have terms, which describe objects.
但是与命题逻辑不同 我们也有些描述对象的项
Now the atomic sentences are predicates corresponding to relations.
原子语句是关系对应的谓词
So we can say, Vowel (A) is an atomic
例如我们可以说 Vowel (A) 是原子语句
sentence or Above (A, B).
或者 Above (A, B) 也是
And we also have a distinguished relation, the equality relation.
我们还有个特别的关系 即相等关系
We can say 2 = 2,
我们可以说 2 = 2
and equality relation is always in every model.
相等关系通常存在于所有模型中
And sentences can be combined with all the operators from propositional logic.
语句通常由命题逻辑中的所有运算符组合起来
So, that's and, or, not, implies, equivalent, and parentheses.
包括 ∧ ∨ ¬⇒ ⇔ 和 ()
Now terms which refer to objects can be constants, like A, B, and 2.
表示对象的项通常是常量 如 A B 和 2
It can be variables, we normally use lowercase like x and y.
也可以是变量 我们通常用小写字母 x 和 y
And they can be functions, like number of (A), which is just another name,
也可以是函数 例如 number of (A) 只是
or another expression that refers to the same object as 1,
对表示同一个对象 1 的另一个名字或另一种表达
the least in the model that we showed previously.
至少是我们之前展现模型中的内容
And then there's one more type of complex sentence, besides the sentences
除了我们通过组合连接符得到语句 让一阶逻辑更加独特外
we get by combining operators that makes first order logic unique.
还有一种更加复杂的语句
And these are the quantifiers.
这些是量词
And there are two quantifiers.
这里有两个量词
For all,
对于全称量词
we write with an upside down A followed by a variable that it introduces.
我们使用 ∀ 后面是引出的变量
And there exists, which we write with an upside down E,
对于存在量词 这里我们使用 ∃
followed by a variable that it introduces.
后面是引出的变量
So for example, we could say, for all x,
例如我们可以说 ∀ x
if x is a vowel, then the number of x is equal to one.
∀ x Vowel (x) ⇒ Number of (x) = 1
And that's a valid sentence in first order logic.
这是一阶逻辑中的有效语句
Or we could say, there exists an x
或者我们可以说 ∃ x
such that the number of (x) = 2.
如 number of (x) = 2
And this is saying that there's some object in the domain to
这就是说域内一些对象
which the number of function applies and has a value of 2, but
可以使用函数 number of 值为 2
we're not saying what that object is.
但是我们无法说明对象是什么
Now another note is that sometimes as an abbreviation, we'll omit the quantifier.
另外需要提醒的是 有时候作为简写形式 我们会省略量词
And when we do that, you can just assume that it means for all,
当我们这样做时 你可以只假设它表示 ∀
that's left out just as a shortcut.
这种省略可以看作一种捷径
And I should say that these forms of these sentences are typical.
我应该说这些语句的形式比较典型
And you'll see these forms over and over again.
你可以不断看到这些形式
So typically, whenever we have a for
所以一般说来 无论何时我们使用
all quantifier introduced, it tends to go with a conditional.
全称量词 它可以匹配一个有条件的量词
Like vowel(x) implies number of (x) = 1.
例如 Vowel (x) 推出 number of (x) = 1
And the reason is, because we usually don't want to say something about
原因在于我们通常不会说明
every object in the domain, since the objects can be so different.
域内的每个对象 因为对象各不相同
But rather we want to say something about a particular type of object.
不过我们会说对象的某个特殊类型
Say, in this case, vowels.
例如在这种情况下是原因
And also, typically when we have an exists an X or exists any variable,
另外一般来说我们存在一个 X 存在任何变量
that typically goes with just a form like this and not with the conditional.
通常都与这样的形式匹配 而不是条件式
Because we're talking about just one object that we want to describe.
因为我们只讨论想要描述的一个对象